I will teach you I am a professor you told me
я тебя научу я профессор ты мне сказал
openly about purchasing
открыт про паритет покупательной
power parity it is how much you
способности он состоит в том сколько ты
can buy with your salary Look I
можешь купить на свою зарплату Смотри я
can buy four times more iPhones
могу купить в четыре раза больше Айфонов
than you I can buy five times more
чем ты Я могу купить в пять раз больше
Samsungs than you for my salary I can
Самсунгов чем ты за свою зарплату я могу
buy food 10 times more than you, yes I
еды купить в 10 раз больше чем ты да я
can pay for an apartment three times I
могу за квартиру заплатить в три раза я
can E pay for three apartments when you
могу Э платить за три квартиры когда ты
pay for
заплатишь за
one Hello
одну Привет
guys Hello hello
мужики Привет привет Вы
Where are you from Krasnoyarsk Territory Narilsk O
откуда Красноярский край нарильск О
cool Norilsk Nickel my dad
прикольно Норникель у меня батя там
worked there under the
работал при
Union, respect yours I’m from Rostov myself But I’ve
Союзе уважуха твоя Я сам с Ростова Но
been living in Europe for 18 years already in Brussels
живу в Европе 18 лет уже в Брюсселе
in 2 years it will be 20, it’s
через 2 года будет двадцатом у вас в
cold in Norilsk, it’s probably like hard
Норильске холодно наверно что
min 30, my dad also says that it’s
жесть мину 30 вот батя тоже говорю что
just really cold there
там холода просто жесть
Yes and  how
Да и как
to survive yes Usually that we survive warmer
выживает да Обычно что выживаем потеплее
We dress more tightly we
Одеваемся покрепче
drink well
пьём
How do you feel about the fact that Russia
градусо как относитесь к тому что Россия
is at war with
воюет с
Ukraine  we don’t like We, in short, these
Украиной не любим Мы короче вот эти
provocative things
провокационные воче
In short, look, we just came in just to
Короче смотри мы короче зашли чисто так
chat and We lived there back and forth already
пообщаться а Жили были там туда-сюда уже
honestly Okay, come on, let’s talk about life,
честно Окей давай давай давай о жизни
just about
просто о
life, and why did you move Why did you decide to
жизни а что что переехал Почему решил
move Damn, well, look, look at
переехать Блин ну слушай смотри в пенсия
my dad’s pension  in this in Rostov 17,000 rubles
у моего бати в этом в Ростове 17.000 руб
is 170 dollars, but here
это 170 долларов да вот а у
I am. My salary is 6,000 euros, that’s
меня У меня зарплата 6.000 евро это там
more than 600,000 there  ruble, in your opinion,
больше 600.000 рубле по вашему то как ты
why do you think I moved and
думаешь почему Я переехал а ценники у
your price tags are cheaper than in Rila,
вас це цены дешевле чем чем на рильский
definitely cheaper? Well, let’s say an apartment
однозначно Ну ну допустим квартира
How much does it cost you there, roughly speaking, 100
Сколько у вас стоит там грубо говоря 100
square meters are the same prices as in
квадратов такие же самые цены как и в
Rostov, anyway, yes So  same thing Well,
Ростове вот по-любому да Так же само Ну
how much do you have t Tell me Yes, I, for example,
сколько у вас т Расскажи Да я я например
rent a two-room apartment 100
снимаю двухкомнатные апартаменты 100
euros 10,000 rubles according to you Why don’t
евро 10.000 руб по ваше А почему не
they buy all the housing and it’s not customary for us
покупают все жильё а у нас не принято
to buy Because  you can, for example,
покупать Потому что ты можешь например
today You can work in one
сегодня Ты можешь работать в одном
city tomorrow in another or in one
городе завтра в другом или в одном
area of ​​the Megalopolis then in another And we
районе Мегаполиса потом в другом И мы
choose housing closer to work like this Well it
выбираем жильё ближе к работе вот так Ну
turns out to be local Who is there, they are essentially
получается местный Кто там э они по сути
local They buy and rent to us Who
местные Они покупают и сдают э нам Кто
came from
приехал из
Russia  uh, among the locals there are those who
России ээ среди местных есть те которые
buy domats, there are those who rent,
покупают домат есть те которые снимают
among the visitors there are also. I have a
среди приезжих также есть Вот у меня
friend from Russia, he moved, yes, he
знакомый из России он э переехал да он
bought three apartments Yes, he rents out two of them, he
купил вот три квартиры Да Две сдаёт в
lives in one. Yes, for example, I’m interested
одной живёт Да мне например интересно
because my work is related
потому что у меня работа связана
we are building development and it turns out there are
девелопмент мы строим и получается есть
objects we are building in one uh on one
объекты мы строим в одном ээ в одной
side of Brussels then in the other side of
стороне Брюсселя потом в другой стороне
Brussels and for example I need to
Брюсселя и мне например нужно порядка
live there for about two years for example to be
дву лет жить например там чтобы быть
close to react Well because it means
близко реагировать Ну потому что это
driving through the whole city Yes for example And so
ехать через весь город Да например А так
you sit down once  minimizes that is, for us
ты сели раз минимизирует то есть у нас
it’s very normal for us. The thing is that,
это очень нормально у нас Дело в том что
like in the Soviet Union, here’s how we lived; no
как в совке вот мы как жили у нас ни у
one had housing at all, and therefore
кого вообще не было жилья и поэтому
to get a shorter one or buy
получить короче или там купить
a one-room apartment there, all this was the top, yes,
однокомнатную всё это было вершина да
plus, for example, it happens  so what are
плюс например Бывает такое что э ты вот
you, here you are When you buy from me, dad Yes, it’s
ты Когда покупаешь вот у меня батя Да он
like in this Soviet Khrushchev apartment In short, they
как в совковой этой хрущёвке Короче они
got it during the Soviet
при совке получили так
era and they still live there and the area is already
до сих пор там и живут там уже район
decrepit Yes and so on they still
дряхлый Да и так дальше они всё равно
live there And here it turns out you,
там живут А тут тут получается ты
for example  you rent an apartment yes You
например снимаешь квартиру да Всё ты
see a more interesting Promising
видишь более интересный Перспективный
area so the economy is developing more there
район так там больше развивается
there are parks and so on you
экономика там парки и так дальше ты там
rent there you rent
берёшь снимаешь
everything And how much does it cost to rent an apartment in
всё А сколько стоит снять квартиру в
Brussels I’m telling you  I rent for a hundred
Брюсселе Я же говорю я за соточку
for a month Yes 100 euros
снимаю на месяц Да 100 евро
Yes 100 euros 100 euros yes 10,000 10,000
Да 100 евро 100 евро да 10.000 10.000
rubles 10,000 rubles yes deuce no deuce
руб 10.000 руб да двоечка нет двойка
apartments A deuce Yes and the communal apartment who
апартаменты А двойка Да а коммуналку кто
pays not and plus the communal apartment Yes the
платит не и плюс коммуналка Да
communal apartment costs 50 euros This is quite the case with winter The
коммуналка выходит 50 евро Это с зимой
maximum that came out was 50  euro
совсем вот Максимум что выходило 50 евро
Well, you know, if I get 6,000 euros,
Ну понимаешь Если я получаю 6.000 евро
then spend it  100 for an apartment and 50 for a
да то потратить 100 на квартиру и 50 на
communal apartment, that’s okay. It’s just that in
коммуналку это ну ничего Да просто мне в
Russia, I know you’ll
России мне топли зна
take fuel to work. Come on, we have transport.
возьмёшь на работу Давай у нас транспорт
Maybe there are all-terrain vehicles where you can put an all-
есть Может там есть вездеходы куда
terrain vehicle. We
присунуть нене там вездеход вездеходом
don’t
не
need an all-terrain vehicle. We don’t need truck tractors, there are platforms
надо у нас седельные тягачи там площадки
here and there.  My dad also
туда-сюда отправим в року мне батя тоже
tells me that in short, damn,
да рассказывает что короче блин так у
you have these prices there, you have everything there, I
вас там эти цены у вас там всё я н батю
brought my dad to Brussels, so here I am  I’m telling him this
привёз в Брюссель по вот ему я ему так
in short, look at you
говорю короче на тебе смотри
guys can’t stand it
пацаны не выдерж
Hello Hello What’s
Здравствуйте Здравствуйте Что у вас
written on your T-shirt is
написано на футболке
interesting Africa and Africa Everything I just
интересно Африка а Африка Всё я просто
saw the top Yes, what connects you with
верхушку видел Да что вас связывает с
Africa is nothing T-shirt I just understood and
Африкой ничего футболка только понял а
you America What connects me I live in
вас Америка Что связывает Я живу в
California I myself come from  Rostov But I’ve
Калифорнии Я сам родом из Ростова Но 18
been living in California for 18 years, in 2 years I’ll be
лет живу в Калифорнии через 2 года будет
20. Where are you from? From what city? I’m
двадцатом А вы откуда Из какого города Я
from Russia, from Tyumen, and Tyumen is like in
с России с Тюмени а Тюмень ну как как в
America if you look at my father in
Америке если смотрите у моего отца в
Rostov 19,000 rubles salary Oh no
Ростове 19.000 руб зарплата Ой не
salary And the pension is 1990 dollars and I have
зарплата А пенсия 1990 долларов а у меня
a small salary
небольшая зарплата
at the university 9,000 dollars 900,000
в университете 9.000 долларов 900.000
rubles in your opinion, well, what do you think no no
руб по-вашему ну как вы думаете нет нет
no no 9,000 dollars This is definitely a lie,
нет нет 9.000 долларов Это точно враньё
look at the salary of a teacher in
посмотри зарплата преподавателя
California, my salary is still small there is
Калифорнии это у меня ещё маленькая есть
more and  You have a teacher, yes, but
больше а вы преподавателя имеете да а
I’m all about You just say scholarship It did
всё я по Вы просто говорите стипендия
n’t seem like a scholarship to me. I’m a
Мне показалось не стипендия Я
teacher. We  We’re talking about salaries
преподаватель Мы же про зарплаты говорим
No, well, look, I understand, yes, that’s it, but
Нет ну смотрите я понимаю да всё но
again, you
опять
know purchasing power parity. Yes, I know, for example, what
знаете такую Да знаю например что такое
parity is. I’m an economics teacher,
паритет Я преподаватель экономики как
just purchasing power parity.
раз паритет покупательной способности
For some reason, all Russians flood me with
мне почему-то все россияне залят паритет
purchasing power parity. So
покупательной способности считается Так
how many goods can you buy?  with your
сколько вы можете товаров купить на свою
salary. Let's do the math. I
зарплату Вот давайте посчитаем я Айфонов
can buy 6 iPhones with my salary alone.
могу на одну свою зарплату купить 6 с
How many iPhones can you buy with your salary?
поно штук сколько вы на свою зарплату
So, your iPhone is a
купите Айфонов Так у вас же iPhone это
local manufacturer again,
же местный производитель ещё раз ещё раз
no, look again  No, wait, wait,
нет смотри Нет так подожди Подождите Нет
No, let me agree
давайте я договорюсь
iPhone Here you are Again, you seem to live in
iPhone Вот вы Опять же типа живёте в
America, but it shows me that you are from
Америке но мне показывает что вы с
Ukraine, I installed a VPN with the Ukrainians, I
Украины я ставил VPN с украинцами
talked to these, let’s take
общался пере эти давайте давайте возьмём
America Yes America America yes America
Америку Да Америка Америка да Америка
sells iPhones, er, produces them in its
продаёт Айфоны ээ производит у себя в
country and  sells in his country which
стране и продаёт в своей стране которые
Chinese afo there is no parity I am an
китайские афо нет паритет я Я
economics teacher If you
преподаватель экономики Если ты
look at purchasing
посмотришь паритет покупательной
power parity and not just listen to what they
способности а не просто послушаешь Что
told you on TV, it doesn’t matter what it
тебе сказали по телевизору неважно чтоо
doesn’t burn  it’s important that where Well let’s
горить не важно что где Хорошо давай про
look about Nokia let’s look at Samsung Let’s
Nokia посмотрим давай про Samsung Давай
Samsung is made in South Korea I
Samsung производится в Южной Корее я на
can buy six Samsungs with my salary
свою зарплату могу купить шесть
but the latest modification is 2 che
Самсунгов но новейшей модификации 2 че
24 plus M How much do they cost you m
24 плюс М А сколько они у вас стоят м
floor 1500 dollars 1000 if exactly its
пол 1500 долларов 1000 если точно сво
1488 dollars Yeah  Can you drop
1488 долларов Угу А можете скинуть э
this
этот
one you can google nfl - this is a
ты ты можешь загугли nfl - это налог на
personal income tax let's
доходы физических лиц давайте давайте
google it so so should I google Samsung
загуглю так так что мне гуглить Samsung
Samsung  s20 no no no about profitability
Samsung s20 нет нет нет про доходность
Samsung - this is us what profitability are
Samsung - это мы что доходность
you talking about income
вы говорите про доход
yat income income income 9 9000 dollars google
ять доход доход 9 9000 долларов загугли
teacher
преподаватель
California
Калифорнии
California salary there will be more than
Калифорнии зарплата там будет больше
nine even so dnat now
девяти даже так днат сейчас
naked so on average so average so
нагу так в среднем так средняя так
California
Калифорния
nana thousand dollars per
нанана тысяч долларов в
year divide  for
год делим на
12 this is how much we get
12 это сколько у нас получается
six will be
шестёрочка будет
oh so yeah Oh
ой так угу Ой
what is
что
it like now Well yes 6 from to and this is you for
так сейчас Ну да 6 с по и это ты за
what year in general on
какой год вообще на
Google I divided no salary you  here's
гуглил я поделил нет зарплату ты вот
70,000 for what year did you get a salary for
70.000 ты за какой год зарплату за
two thousand or for which one
двухтысячный или за какой
did you get it, yes exactly for two Well, take the average
взял да точно за дву Ну возьми средняя
salary like California 2024
зарплата типа Калифорния 2024 год
gu professor professors earn
гу профессор профессора зарабатывают
Exactly more than
Точно больше
100,000 you googled something wrong And the price
100.000 ты что-то не то на гуглил А цену
So wait wait let's talk about income
Так подождите подожди ты давай про доход
Come on  first about income Dial professor
Давай сначала про доход Набери профессор
California salary about nene it gave me
Калифорния зарплата про нене выдало мне
I was given an average of 70 what are you
Мне выдало вот в среднем 70 что ты какой
saying what website look  look look I'm writing
сайт скажи смотри посмотри смотри Я пишу
the salary di America stage America I'm the
зарплату ди Америка стадия Америка я вот
very first just stage
самый первый просто стадия
America
Америка
like that And you're sitting here from America
так так А вы же с Америки сидите У вас
I'm looking I'm looking don't wait I go
же я смотрю я смотрю не подожди я захожу
to your Yandex and look for it
в вашем Яндексе ищу а
huh Yes what's the difference where you found
угу Да какая разница там же где ты нашёл
70  in the same place, what difference does it make where you log
70 там же какая разница где Вы заходите
into Yandex, in the same place, using your IP address, requests for environments, in the
в Яндекс там же по айпишник запросы сред
same place, using your IP address, requests. You can
там же по айпишник запросы Ты можешь
choose
выбирать
the region
регион
where you write Count, two crops and  you write Russia
где пишешь Count дву кроп и пишешь Раша
and that’s all that’s the problem, look 129,000
и всё в чём проблема вот смотри 129000
dollars average salary Yandek so far Where
долларов средняя зарплата Яндек пока Где
where in California professor link
где в Калифорнии профессор ссылку
Please post it on Google in your place
Скиньте пожалуйста так на Гугле у себя
or in Yandex Type Well, you Googled it
или в Яндексе Набери Так вы же загуглили
for me, you can Just the link I’m telling you again,
мне можете Просто ссылку я тебе ещё раз
look at it again, look  a
говорю смотри у ещё раз смотри у
professor in California doesn’t have less than
профессора в Калифорнии нету меньше
100,000 a year. How much do you pay for an apartment?
100.000 в год А сколько вы за квартиру
wait, let’s
платите подожди давай мы сейчас с
figure out the income now, then  no we we
доходом разберёмся значит нет мы мы
will figure it out look you are not Troy you are jumping
разберёмся смотри ты Не Трои ты прыгаешь
from afo you are jumping No I am not jumping Look
с афо ты спрыгина Нет я не прыгаю Смотри
I m you because we just
я м ты потому что мы только что тебя
[ __ ] you in short for the iPhone you jumped for the
поимели короче за iPhone ты спрыгнул за
iPhone because we [ __ ] you for the
iPhone потому что мы тебя поимели за
Samsung you started checking Or are
Samsung ты начал проверять Или
they really here  I
действительно тут такие зарплаты
just got my salary, look, even if you
залез просто да вот смотри даже если ты
get 6,000 dollars a year Oh,
нагулино 6.000 долларов в год Ой в месяц
I wouldn’t have nine a month Let six be
у меня было бы не девять Пусть а шесть
four Samsung Now  tell me how much
это четыре Самсунга Теперь скажи сколько
you will buy half a Samsung with your meager salary.
ты на свою нищенски зарплату купишь
That is, I, wait, I don’t
Самсунга То есть я я подождите я не знаю
just know how much a Samsung costs, well, look.
просто сколько Samsung стоит ну посмотри
So how much about which Samsung? We’re talking about the
Так сколько про какой Samsung Мы говорим
twenty-fourth s24. Come on. How much does
а двадцать четвёртый s24 Давай Сколько
it cost you? Let me
Вот он у вас стоит Давай так сейчас
say this now, well, this  Well, again, under
скажу сейчас ну это ж опять же под
sanction, come on, yes yes Well, I don’t know, it’s not
санкция давай да да Ну я не знаю это не
like that with us
у нас так
72 Well, I ri Well, 3 with pono I can afford Samsung
72 Ну я ри Ну 3 с поно могу себе Samsung
How much does Samsung cost you
Сколько стоит Samsung у вас
like s24  for 256 GB onx 82.000 s24 p
так s24 на 256 ГБ onx 82.000 s24 п
look I told you plus yes yes you
смотри я тебе плюс говорил да да ты
will tell me okay Okay ok 800
расскажешь мне хорошо Хорошо о'кей 800
dollars Okay then I look I
долларов О'кей тогда я смотри я таких
can buy such Samsungs it turns out uh
Самсунгов могу купить получается ээ Во
So what difference does it make how many Samsungs you can
так какая разни сколько ты можешь
That's how it is parity
Самсунгов Вот так это есть паритет
purchasing power you I
покупательной способности тыж я тебе я
will teach you I'm a professor you told me
тебя научу я профессор ты мне сказал
purchasing power parity is open
открыт паритет покупательной способности
it consists of how much you can
он состоит в том сколько ты можешь
buy with  your salary Look, I can
купить на свою зарплату Смотри я могу
buy four times more iPhones than
купить в четыре раза больше Айфонов чем
you I can buy five times more
ты Я могу купить в пять раз больше
Samsungs than you for my salary I can
Самсунгов чем ты за свою зарплату я могу
buy 10 times more food than you yes
еды купить в 10 раз больше чем ты да я
I can pay three times the rent I
могу за квартиру заплатить в три раза я
can pay for three  apartments when you
могу платить за три квартиры когда ты
pay for one you say
заплатишь за одну сказываешь
Let’s start with parity I love
Давай сначало паритет Я так люблю
purchasing power parity so much I don’t
паритет покупательной способности Я не
know what they are there and where they counted them on
знаю что они там и где считали им по
TV they said that Russia is the top one
телику сказали что Россия топ один
in terms of purchasing
короче по паритету покупательной
power parity  this is how much you
способности это ж и есть то сколько ты
can buy with your salary, yes, your
можешь купить на свою зарплату да твой
consumer cats are a basket if a
потребительский кошек это корзина если
person is in California Yes, they calculate
человек в Калифорнии Да они там считают
the rent there Kato You look, a
квартплату там ещё Като Вы посмотрите
person in California with his salary
человек в Калифорнии на свою зарплату
can buy more phones, more cars,
может купить больше телефонов больше
more washing machines, more
тачек больше стиральных машинок больше
apartments Yes  and apartments They think,
квартир Да и квартиры Они же мыслят
you know why I’m laughing, since the Russians they
понимаете за что я ржу ещё с русских они
think, these are the ones they think, they
мыслят вот этих они мыслят они
compare their apartment in Khrushchev yes with a
сравнивают свою квартиру в хрущёвки Да с
communal apartment with a house in America with a house
коммунал кой с домом в Америке с домом
There’s a damn two-story  a house with this
Там блин двухэтажный дом с этим
and territory Yes, and so on And so on Yes, and they
с территорией Да ещё и так дальше Да и
compare expenses on a house Yes with their
сравнивают траты на дом Да со своей
shorter bark like pancake Communal Okay, let's
короче корой типа блин Коммунальной
go, this is generally
Ладно поехали это мне вообще
interesting to me, I speak Russian I am originally
интересно я по-русски говорю Я сам родом
from Rostov, I just live in California 18
из Ростова просто живу в Калифорнии 18
years in 2 years  Where are you
лет через 2 года будет дто Вы
from? Do you speak Ukrainian or speak I
откуда те по украински говорить или по Я
don’t understand Ukrainian? I’m from Rostov-on-Don,
не понимаю по-украински Я из Ростова
you have the
родо у тебя
American flag declared on the back
у флаг Америки декларируется сзади
because as I say, I live in
потому что я же говорю я живу в
California, this is the state of California  I’ve
Калифорнии это штат Калифорния 18 лет
already been living for 18 years. I’m a university teacher
уже живу Я преподаватель университета
there, in 2 years there will be a twentieth, but my
там вот через 2 года будет Двадцатый но
parents are originally from
родом из Ростова родители у меня в
Rostov. And why do you have a
Ростове А почему у тебя флаг
different flag? Yes, look, I put Ukraine, I
другой Да я смотри я ставил Украину я
talked to Ukrainians like I’m Ukrainian Yes,
общался с украинцами типа Я украинец Да
because and then I say Russian And  they
потому что а потом говорю русс И они
start yelling at me so I checked
начинают на меня орать вот я проверял
how they change when they find out that I
как они меняются когда узнают что я
[music]
[музыка]
ru Far East Russia Usuriysk
ру Дальний Восток Россия Усурийск
Khabarovsk free
Хабаровск свободный
city
город
Vladivostok no
Владивосток нет
Khabarovsk to from Khabarovsk I
Хабаровск к от Хабаровска у меня тка в
live in Urik
урике жит
What am I talking about about the World Cup I saw you on
О чём разговариваю о ЧМ Я видел вас в
tiktok Well not on tiktok I saw how you
тиктоке Ну не в тиктоке Я видел как вы
treat Russia
относитесь к России
negatively I’m not positive I’m positive about the
негативно не я позитивно я к власти
Russian authorities I’m a Russian myself I can’t relate to
Российской я сам россиянин я не могу к
Russia  have a negative
России негативно
attitude Why are you bringing to power
относиться А почему вы несёте к власти
Well, to the Russian power How
Ну к власти Российской Как вы
can you, let me speak the same
можете давайте я буду говорить пому
language Why are you
языку Почему вы
unwinding Well about Russia well negative Well about
размот Ну про Россию ну негативно Ну про
Russian authorities once again because
российскую власть ещё раз потому что
look I was born in Rostov and grew up my
смотри Я родился в Ростове и вырос мои
parents mom dad in Rostov how do I
родители мама папа в Ростове как у меня
question how in our richest country
вопрос как в нашей богатейшей стране в
which has oil gold gas diamonds Yes
которой есть нефть золото газ алмазы Да
my father receives a 20,000 ruble
мой отец получает 20.000 руб
pension Well
пенсии Ну
20,000 how funny is that funny true
20.000 как это смешно смешно правда
Because  that in California I receive
Потому что я в Калифорнии получаю 99.000
a salary of 99,000 dollars as a teacher, this is
долларов зарплату как преподаватель это
900,000 rubles
900.000 руб
in Russian Well, yes, your dad receives
по-русски Ну да твой папа получает
20,000 Yes, a pension  Yes, a pension Yes, I am a
20.000 Да пенсию Да пенсию Да а Я
disabled person of the third group. I get 15,000.
инвалид третьей группы Я получаю 15.000
And
И
I didn’t expect a pension of 15,150 dollars.
что не надеялась 15 150 долларов пенсии
Well, that is, in a country where there is
Ну да то есть в стране в которой есть
oil, gas, gold and diamonds, 150 dollars, a
нефть газ золото и алмазы 150 долларов
pension of 15 rubles.
пенсия 15 руб
Yes, you How much do you pay for an apartment for
Да ты Сколько платишь за квартиру за
your 200 dollars 200
свою 200 долларов 200
dollars  and I’ll get And I pay 300 rubles for my
долларов а я получу А я плачу за свою
apartment,
квартиру 300
so look, I’ll have some left over, I’ll have
руб ну так смотри у меня остатся у меня
some left over after 9000 and 200  there will be 8,800 dollars left
остатся после 9000 ми 200 остатся 8.800
88,000
88.000
rubles yes And I have plus another
руб да А у меня плюс ещё
benefit, plus or minus a benefit In short, even
льгота плюс-минус льгота Короче ты даже
look at your benefits, you should
смотри с твоими льготами ты ты должен
receive for several years So much to
получать несколько лет Столько чтобы
get as much as I get per
получить столько сколько я получаю за
month for years to pay, let’s
месяц за года платить давай так
do the math, look, your pension is 15,000
посчитаем смотри у тебя пенсия 15.000
rubles  12 months is 150 p 30 180,000 rubles
руб 12 месяцев это 150 п 30 180.000 руб
you get for a year  180,000 rubles
тебе Ты за год получаешь 180.000 руб
pension for you to get as much
пенсии тебе чтобы получить столько
as I do in a month 900,000 rubles you
сколько я за месяц 900.000 руб тебе
need 5 years to
нужно 5 лет пенсию
receive a pension again, look again I am a
получать ещё раз смотри Я преподаватель
university teacher in California getting 99,000
университета в Калифорнии получаю 99.000
dollars a month for 900,000 rubles you are a
долларов в месяц за 900.000 руб ты
disabled pensioner in Russia Yes, you get
пенсионер в России инвалид Да получаешь
that much in 5 years
столько за 5 лет
Yes, and you say  that this is
Да и ты говоришь что это
right Yes this is
правильно Да это
correct And what is correct Well look
правильно А в чём правильно Ну смотри
if our Russia has gold oil
если у нашей России есть золото нефть
gas Almaz Why can’t you have a pension
газ Алмаза Почему у тебя пенсия не может
45,000 rubles and not 15 and why does your
быть 45.000 руб а не 15 а почему у вас
rice cost? So, here it costs
рис стоит Так а у нас стоит так
ri for us, this is where I am, with us, ri
у нас ри вот где я нахожусь у нас ри
costs 50
стоит 50
rubles, and how much in California in
руб а у вас сколько в Калифорнии в
California does it cost ri for your money, 70
Калифорнии стоит ри на ваши деньги 70
rubles? Well, why with this  the amount you have
руб Ну и почему при этой сумме у вас
is 70 rubles and ours is 50 rubles
стоит 70 руб а у нас стоит 50 руб потому
because our salary is 60 times more than
что у нас зарплата в 60 раз больше чем у
your pension,
тебя пенсия
bags of rice that you just need to mortgage the whole
мешков риса что залож просто короче всю
house, you understand And yes, I’m on  And
хату понимаешь А да я на А я на свою
I don’t even work on my pension. I can
пенсию я даже не работаю Я могу свою
mortgage my house. Well, that’s not the truth.
хату заложить Ну не эту правда у меня
I still have another house. I’m
другая хата ещё есть я сейчас нахожусь
at
на
work right now. I have a
работе У меня
three-room apartment in the city of Svobodny. Well, look, a three-room apartment in the
Хорошо смотри трёхкомнатная квартира
city of Svobodny. Explain to me,
город Свободный Объясни мне вот ну
simply, where does it go in our  Russia Where
просто Куда девается в нашей России Куда
does all the money go oil gas gold and
деваются все деньги нефти газа золота и
diamond not not your Russia not in your
алмаз не не вашей России не в вашей
Russia well you can never have politics anymore
России ну уже нельзя никогда политику
Look Look there is such a picture
Посмотрите Посмотрите есть такая картина
uh Brother 2 says well Brother 2 looked
ээ Брат 2 говорит ну Брат 2 смотрели
yes you know there  this was the main character
да знаете там такой был главный герой
Yes, Dmitry
Да Дмитрий
would be shorter, the main character here
там бы короче главный герой вот Напишите
Just write Brother 2 How he feels about
просто Брат 2 Как он относится к
politics And how he feels about politics And what is his
политике И что как он
attitude he
относится он вам там
will answer you there literally in the youtube just type it for
ответит буквально в юбе просто наберите
you I
он вам я
understand correctly that you live in life with
правильно понимаю что ты в жиз
the instructions of some artistic
инструкциями какого-то художественного
character
персонажа
invented
придуманного
No, well, that is, some screenwriter
Нет ну то есть какой-то сценарист
wrote a script, an actor shot a film in it
написал сценарий снял фильм в нём актёр
Said some phrase and for you this is
Сказал какую-то фразу и для тебя это
authority no You are wrong What did
авторитет нет Вы не правы А что так что
this Pavlo say,
сказал Этот Павло
not what he said, I
брол не то что он сказал я вам хочу
just want to tell you  one thing is that you
только сказать одно то что никогда
can never keep
нельзя
your
свою
country, no matter what it
страну какой бы она ни
is. When
была Когда
there is
проходит
a special operation. When there is a war, you can
спецоперация Когда проходит война нельзя
never keep your country. I
свою страну никогда нете свою страну я я
understand correctly that this hero in Brother
правильно понимаю что этот герой в Брат
2 said that when there is a
2 говорил что когда проходит
special operation wound, he said so Yes,
спецоперация рану он так и сказал Да
wait, wait there you  when you score you
подожди Подожди там ты когда забьёшь сам
'll hear yourself you'll
услышишь
hear I'll speak correctly Let me finish Let me
услышите буду говорить правильно Дайте
agree
договорить Дайте
Yes
Да
Listen Well, you're live, you
Слушайте Ну ты прямой ты прямую
turned on the live broadcast As a result, you turned off the sound
трансляцию включил В итоге выключил звук
yes yes, I'm listening to you, let's tell me
да да я слушаю тебя давай расска ты мне
five times  you tell me
пять раз рассказываешь дай дослушать
let me listen to the end let me interrupt then
давай меня тогда перебивает
I’m silent
я молчу
Speak here
Говори вот
listen When there is
слушайте Когда проходит
a special operation or
спецоперация либо
war no matter how it is or no matter how it
война как бы она ни была или как оно не
will be Let’s say Yeah,
будет Допустим Ага вот
listen to such a
выслушайте такой
person listen no matter how it is how
человек слушайте как бы оно не было как
it won’t
оно не
be there they said never their
будет там сказали никогда не свою
power
власть
Yeah  When all this has passed, then you
Ага Когда пройдёт вот это вот всё тогда
can already
уже можно хоть что
say something. And at the moment, when it’s all
говорить А в данный момент когда
passing, this is how it is
проходит Вот это всё так оно и
[laughter]
[смех]
let me finish, interrupt me, I’m already
будет дай договорить перебивай я уже
silent again.
молчу опять
Maybe
Может
he needs meaning so that  they interrupted him, he
смыс ему нужно чтобы его перебивали он
can’t formulate a thought for more than 15
не может сформулировать мысль дольше 15
seconds
секунд
about I love it so much when Russians appeal
про Я так люблю когда русский апеллируют
to some phrase from the film Brother 2, and you
какой-то к фразе из фильма Брат 2 да ещё
know, Soon they will be there, what’s Bura
знаете Скоро они будут что там Бура
skaz in skaz, read Burari, a
сказа в сказ почитай бурари
fictional character from the film, said something to them
вымышленный персонаж из фильма что-то им
and  they are
сказал и они
now sitting, it is clear that the person in the
теперь сидит видно что человек
poorest Russia has oil gold gas
беднейшим Россия имее нефть золото газ
diamonds and he must live in such poverty
алмазы и он должен жить в такой нищете
Yes, he has no feast Yes like subscribe Komen
Да он нет пира Да лайк подписка комен
subscribe to Telegram directly  conv axis VN and
подпишись на Telegram пря зараз ось ВН а
so far more and more respectfully YouTube has occupied
пок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us through a sgr tvy ban and even more
нас через сгр твый бан и дуже багато
richly video I don’t show people constantly I don’t show
вдео не показую людям вчасно не показуе
information about streams for this purpose for
информация про стримы тому для того щоб
Mali operational link to write
ми Мали оперативный звязок пишиться
directly at the same time and while there in telegra okm
прямо зараз а пок там в телегра окм
video
видео
tazhka and  korisna information and we are sorry
тежка и корисна информация и мы повинни
for you trimati postiyny operational
з вами тримати постийний оперативный
link
звязок
Nezalezhno in that chi show you about Tsei
незалежно в того чи покаже вам про Цей
YouTube Glory to Ukraine
YouTube Слава Украине
write L
пиши L